# Yizheng Jiao

704 Martin Luther King Jr. Blvd Apt D8, Chapel Hill, N.C. 27514 **Phone:** +1 (919) 914-1794 **Email:** yizheng@cs.unc.edu Github: jyizheng

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests focus on the design and implementation of efficient and secure data management system. I am doing research on write-optimized index data structures for high-speed storage system. In my research projects, I am developing a general-purpose in-kernel file system on Linux which has compelling performance on micro-write intensive workloads. I am also exploring the potentials of writeoptimzed data strutures in designing secure persistent key-value stores with the aid of SGX/TrustZone to protect user's data against malicious Operating System.

## **EDUCATION EXPERIENCE**

Ph.D in Computer Science

Aug. 2016 - Present

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Advisor: Donald Porter Expected graduation date: Aug. 2021

M.S. in Computer Science Stony Brook University Advisor: Donald Porter

Jan. 2014 - Aug. 2016

M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep. 2009 - March. 2012

Huazhong University of Science & Technology Advisor: Feng Bin, Wenyu Liu

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering Chongqing University

Sep. 2005 - Jun. 2009

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

PROFESSIONAL Research Intern Advanced Technology Group, NetApp Inc, Durham, N.C.

**EXPERIENCE** 

Mentor: Michael Condict, Xiongzi Ge

- Optimization of BetrFS for SSD device;
- Integration of in-kernel  $B^{\epsilon}$ -tree key-value store with Linux page cache to reduce overhead of data transport;
- Extended BetrFS to support large block size to reduce meta-data overhead;
- Sequential write performance is increased by 2 times.

Software Engineer Intern

May 2017 - Aug. 2017

vSan Team, VMWare Inc, Palo Alto, C.A.

Mentor: Wenguang Wang, Ding Li

- Optimization of Copy-on-Write B-tree with write-optimized techniques;
- Analysis of snapshot service performance for Virtual Distributed File System (VDFS);
- Implementation of physical block cache for VDFS;
- Read performance is improved by 50%.

Software Engineer

May 2013 - Aug. 2013

Leadership Computing Facility Group, Oak Ridge National Lab, Knoxville, T.N.

Mentor: Sarp Oral

- Implementation of parallel and scalable programs to move and archive large volumes of data on supercomputers;
- Analysis on performance of implemented utilities on Titan supercomputer with hundreds of MPI nodes.

# RESEARCH PROJECTS

#### BetrFS Project

Jan. 2014 - Present

Details could be found at http://www.betrfs.org

- Profing and analyzing BetrFS performance on SSD device;
- Optimizing BetrFS's metadata performance with varied block size;
- Integrating in-kernel  $B^{\epsilon}$ -tree key-value store with Linux page cache;
- Implementing Copy-on-Write page cache to support file system transaction.

## Exploring Contiguity in Memory System

May 2014 - May 2015

- Studying physical page allocator of popular operating systems, such as Linux, Windows, OpenBSD and Solaris OS;
- Studying disk block allocator of file systems , such as Ext4, ZFS;
- Evaluating performance impact of Linux Transparent Hugepages for application with big memory footprint, such as graph processing, k-mer counting for Genome sequences.

## Efficient Data Management for MapReduce Programs May 2013 - Dec 2013

- Enabling memory sharing between map/reduce tasks on the same compute node;
- Accelerating merge phase of MapReduce programs by decoupling values from the K-V pairs during sorting;
- Testing performance of MapReduce programs on Amazon EC2 cluster.

#### Hybrid Memory System for GPU

Aug. 2012 - May 2013

- Hybridizing phrase-change memory and DRAM for GPU global memory;
- Implementing compiler-directed initial data placement for CUDA programs;
- Integrating GPGPU-Sim with DRAMSim2 to simulate GPU global memory system;
- Implementing simulator code to perform hardware-based page migration between PCM and DRAM.

#### PUBLICATIONS [Arxiv]: Yizheng Jiao. Exploring Physical Contiguity in Memory System.

[Submitted to FAST'2021]: Yizheng Jiao, Simon Bertron, Nirjhar Mukherjee, Rory Bennett, Michael A. Bender, Alex Conway, Martin Farach-Colton William Jannen, Rob Johnson, Donald E. Porter, and Jun Yuan. FestiFS: A General-Purpose File System for Commodity SSDs and HDDs.

[FAST'20]: Yang Zhan, Alex Conway, Yizheng Jiao, Nirjhar Mukherjee, Ian Groombridge, Michael A. Bender, Martin Farach-Colton William Jannen, Rob Johnson, Donald E. Porter, and Jun Yuan. *How to Copy Files*.

[ICPR'19]: Wenhui Zhang, Yizheng Jiao, Dazhong Wu, Srivatsa Srinivasa, Asmit De, Swaroop Ghosh, Peng Liu. ArmorPLC: Cyber Security Threats Detection through Ladder Logic Validation for PLCs.

[HotStorage'19]: Alex Conway, Eric Knorr, Yizheng Jiao, Michael A. Bender, William Jannen, Rob Johnson, Donald Porter, Martin Farach-Colton. Filesystem Aging: Its more Usage than Fullness.

[SPAA'19]: Michael A. Bender, Alexander Conway, Martin Farach-Colton, William Jannen, Yizheng Jiao, Rob Johnson, Eric Knorr, Sara McAllister, Nirjhar Mukherjee, Prashant Pandey, Donald E. Porter, Jun Yuan and Yang Zhan. Small Refinements to the DAM Can Have Big Consequences for Data-Structure Design.

[FAST'18]: Yang Zhan, Alex Conway, Yizheng Jiao, Eric Knorr, Michael A. Bender, Martin Farach-Colton, William Jannen, Rob Johnson, Donald E. Porter, Jun Yuan. The Full Path of Full-Path Indexing. Oakland, USA. Feb, 2018.

[FAST'17]: Alex Conway, Ainesh Bakshi, Yizheng Jiao, Yang Zhan, Michael A. Bender, William Jannen, Bradley C. Kuszmaul, Donald Porter, Jun Yuan, Martin Farach-Colton. File System Fated for Senescence? Nonsense, Says Science!. Santa Clara, USA. Feb, 2017.

[SOSP'15]: Chia-Che Tsai, Yang Zhan, Jayashree Reddy, Yizheng Jiao, Tao Zhang, Donald E. Porter. How to Get More Value From Your File System Directory Cache. Monterey, USA. Jan, 2015.

[FAST'15]: William Jannen, Jun Yuan, Yang Zhan, Amogh Akshintala, John Esmet, Yizheng Jiao, Ankur Mittal, Prashant Pandey, and Phaneendra Reddy, Leif Walsh, Michael Bender, Martin FarachColton, Rob Johnson, Bradley C. Kuszmaul, Donald E. Porter. BetrFS: A Right-Optimized Write Optimized File System. Santa Clara, USA. Jan, 2015.

[SC'13]:Xiaobing Li, Yandong Wang, Yizheng Jiao, Cong Xu, Weikuan Yu. Coomr: Cross-Task Coordination for Efficient Data Management in MapReduce *Programs*. Denver, USA. November, 2013.

[PACT'13]:Bin Wang, Bo Wu, Dong Li, Xipeng Shen, Weikuan Yu, Yizheng Jiao, Jeffrey S. Veter. Exploring Hybrid Memory for GPU Energy Efficiency through Software-Hardware Co-Design. Edinburgh, Scotland. September, 2013.

[MASCOT'13]:Bin Wang, Yizheng Jiao, Xipeng Shen, Dong Li, Weikuan Yu. A Versatile Performance and Energy Simulation Tool for GPU global memory. San Francisco, USA. August, 2013.

[BAWD'13]: Yandong Wang, Yizheng Jiao, Cong Xu, Xiaobing Li, Teng Wang Xinyu Yue, Cristi Cira, Bin Wang, Zhuo Liu, Bliss Bailey, Weikuan Yu. Assessing the Performance Impact of HighSpeed Interconnects on MapReduce. 2013.

**SKILLS** 

**TECHNOLOGY** Programming Languages: C, Python, Java Operating System and Services: Linux, AWS Cloud Services, Docker, Jenkins.

# HONORS AWARDS

- Merit Student Scholarship of 2009, 2010, 2011;
- University-Wide Thesis Award of Chongqing University in 2009;
- $\bullet\,$  National Aspiration Scholarship for two time in 2007 and 2009;
- Huawei Scholarship in 2006.